curriculum vitae

2022/03/31 Name: Yoshiki Ohashi

work summary

After graduating from university, joined an information and telecommunications development company. As a system engineer, he was in charge of basic program design and development. Consistently engaged in the development of business systems for the logistics industry. In his second company, he worked for a venture company for two years to experience scratch development from scratch. He gained a wide range of experience from planning and design to development work and sometimes as an IT instructor. He worked as a sole proprietor for about 2 years in order to catch up with modern languages quickly, and experienced development work in various languages with advanced microservices architecture. After that, he joined Rakuten Group, Inc. as a full-time employee because he could not experience "responsible production work" as much as he could with outsourcing contract. Currently, he is in charge of developing a flea market application using Ruby on Rails.

work experience

Rakuten Group, Inc. (Work period: 2021/06 ~ now)

Business: Development and operation of more than 70 services including e-commerce, fintech, digital content, and telecommunications

Period	Project Details	Development Environment	Role/Scale
	楽天/フリマアプリ追加機能開発 バックエンドエンジニアとして新配送機能の開発設計業務		
2021/06 ~ 現在	範囲: 要件定義、機能検討、設計、コーディング、レビュー 詳細: ゆうパケットプラス・ポストに対応する設計・開発、コンビニ受取の 設計・開発。 事業側との開発前のユーザストーリーマッピングを実施。チームの慣 例に毎月KPT振返りを実施。 20億レコードを超えるテーブルにメンテナンスでカラム追加の実施。	Ruby on Rails 5 AWS EC2 Circle CI	メンバー/200名 Business/100名 Develop/100名

Worked as a freelancer (Work period: 2019/04 ~ 2021/05)

Business: Internet service development and operation

Period	Project Details	Development Environment	Role/Scale
2020/11	DCM社/CtoC DIY商品販売ECサイト開発 DIY商品のEC販売サイトの新規開発	Golang(echo) React(TypeScript)	メンバー/15名

2021/05	範囲: 機能検討、設計、コーディング、レビュー 詳細: React, TypeScript によるフロントエンド機能開発 Atomic Designを使用したエコシステムの構築 Cypressを利用したE2Eテスト環境の構築 GitHub Actionsを利用しE2E自動テスト環境の構築	Redux, styled- components, Cypress, Jest GitHub Actions	
2019/10 ~ 2020/10	(株)OPTiM/手術ロボットリアルタイム監視ダッシュボード開発マイクロサービスアーキテクチャで構成. 医療機器(IoT)からPOSTされるレコードをPubSubAPIでDBに保存をし、保存されたデータをリアルタイムにダッシュボードに表示させ、医療従事者に医療現場のログを可視化する価値を提供するシステム開発. 範囲: 機能検討(インセプションデッキ作成・検討)、設計、コーディング、レビュー API: アプリの認証部分(OAuth2)を担当. Spring Cloud Gatewayを使用し、認証情報をGatewayに管理をさせ、フロントとFBBと通信を行うように処理をしました. 実装方針としてはなるべくSpringの機能を最大限活用(Springはエコシステム上最適と判断し選択)Front: Atomic Designの思想でコンポーネント開発. BFF、OAuth2認証、WebSocket, SSEでのリアルタイムデータ表示、Three.jsでロボットリアルタイムモデル再生といった先進的な技術挑戦を経験. 詳細な技術解決内容は <u>こちら</u> に記載しております(https://job-draft.jp/users/45995#resume-header)	Java11 Golang, OpenAPI Spring WebFlux, Spring Boot, SpringCloud Gateway, JOOQ Vue.js, Jest, Atomic Design GitLab CI/CD	メンバー/11名
2019/04 ~ 2019/09	GMO社/蓄電システム顧客管理Webアプリ 既存システムの改修案件に携わる.蓄電システムのWeb管理アプリの PM兼開発者として要件定義-結合フェーズまで担当 範囲:顧客機能提案、設計、コーディング、レビュー 詳細: SpringBootを使用したサーバーサイドAPI改修 フロントの画面開発 バッチ処理の改修(Shell Script) 既存システムDBにFlywayを導入 ・空き時間に改善した内容 チームにIntelliJ IDEA導入,ローカル開発DB構築にDockerの導入, Seleniumを使用した自動テストの導入	Java8, SpringBoot, Thymeleaf, MyBatis jQuery, Selenium Docker, Flyway	PM/4人

Kuronos Inc. (Work period: 2017/04 ~ 2019/03)

Business: AI solutions, web and mobile app development, IT training

Period	Project Details	Development Environment	Role/Scale
2018/06 ~ 2019/03	DMM社/パチンコ・パチスロ情報統合アプリ開発 公共賭博の店舗情報などを公開するスマホアプリのAndroid、iOSア プリの改修案件を担当いたしました. 改修内容としては、単純にアプ	Java(Android) Kotlin Objective-C ButterKnife, PopInfo(通	メンバー/3人

	リの画面開発だけでなく、新機能の追加の際に必要となるAPI項目の 洗出~作成依頼、アプリ側の通信~画面表示までを担当 範囲: 画面設計、設計、コーディング、レビュー 詳細: 既存アプリのバグ改修や新規機能の追加業務を担当 APIチームへ開発に必要なJSONスキーマの連携 チーム内で振り返り手法のKPTを利用し、開発効率の向上 アプリ開発者からAPIチームへの連絡手段が限られる => 別チームにも 気軽に連携できるように工夫	知ライブラリ) GitLab	
2018/01 ~ 2018/04	自社サービス/社員モチベーション管理Webアプリゼロからの開発となりサービスの立ち上げを担当社員のモチベーションを外部GmailやSlack、その他チャットツールを利用し社員のモチベーションをWatsonAPIにより判定させるWebアプリケーション 範囲: 画面設計、設計、コーディング、レビュー 詳細: Kotlin(Spring), Vue.jsでのSPA開発 SlackAPIとの認証処理 フロントからバックエンドにかけてCSVでのユーザ登録機能の作成	Kotlin(Spring) Gradle MySQL, DOMA2 WatsonAPI, SlackAPI, ChatworkAPI AWS EC2, Docker, docker-compose	メンバー/4人
2017/09 ~ 2018/01	情報銀行PoCプロジェクト、旅行提案型Androidアプリ開発 情報銀行としての役割を試験的に検証するためのPoC案件 登録者が詳細な個人情報以外の性格情報等を入力し、入力の代わりに オペレータが観光地の旅行プランを提案するAndroidアプリ 範囲: バックエンド設計、設計、コーディング、レビュー 詳細: Salesforceの基本設定、SalesforceのHeroku ConnectでのDB連携 Heroku Connect側のAPI設計	Apex(Java) Salesforce, Heroku, Heroku Connect, SpringBoot Java(Android)	メンバー/5人
2017/04 ~ 2017/08	官公庁/オリンピックマスコット募集サイト開発ゼロからの開発となりサービスの立ち上げを担当東京オリンピックのマスコットを募集するためのサイト範囲:基本設計,詳細設計、コーディング、レビュー詳細: Salesforceのサイト公開機能を利用し公開ページを作成登録者に向けて仮登録機能、本登録機能、メール送信機能を提供仮登録時に有効期限を1時間としたtoken付きURLの発行複数画像の同時登録機能の提供	Salesforce Site, Apex, Visualforce	メンバー/5人

トリオシステムプランズ Inc.

(Work period: 2016/04 ~ 2017/03)

Business: System development business for manufacturing, distribution, and healthcare

		Environment	
	YONEX/物流システム開発 海外流通のあるスポーツメーカーの内部システムの改修案件に携わる		
2016/04	範囲: 設計、コーディング	Salesforce Java8, SpringBoot thymeleaf, JPA	メンバー/5人
2017/03	詳細: SpringBootフレームワーク上でAPIの追加 関税、国別通貨別の料金計算 商品受注、料金計算を行う画面開発	jQuery, JavaScript	

Skills

Туре	Language	Period	Level
Language	Java8, Java11	★4 Year	I can teach the members
	Kotlin	★1 Year	Immediate results in the business
	Golang	★1 Year	Immediate results in the business
	JavaScript	★3 Year	Immediate results in the business
	TypeScript	★3 Year	Immediate results in the business
DB	MySQL	★2 Year	Have a knowledge
	PostgresSQL	★1 Year	Have a knowledge
Framework	Spring Boot	★3 Year	I can teach the members
	Spring MVC	★1 Year	I can teach the members
	Spring WebFlux	★1 Year	I can teach the members
	Spring Security	★1 Year	Experience in use
	Spring Cloud Gateway	★1 Year	I can teach the members
	Rails	★1 Year	Immediate results in the business
	Vue.js	★2 Year	I can teach the members
	React.js	★2 Year	I can teach the members
	Gatsby.js	1 Year	Personal Development Gatsby Theme開発 (<u>https://github.com/yoshiki-0428/gatsby-all-pack-theme-starter</u>)
	Next.js	1 Year	Personal Development みんなのサブスク (<u>https://review.subsc.cc</u>)
	frourio	0.5 Year	Personal Development in use
CI/CD	GitHub Actions	★1 Year	Experience in use
	Circle CI	★1 Year	Experience in use
	GitLab CI	★1 Year	Experience in use

Qualifications

- TOEIC 500 (2021/07/20)
- Oracle Java Silver SE 8

Self PR

Web application engineer who can design a wide range of applications from back-end to front-end. We use Go, Java, Vue.js, and TypeScript, and can design applications with a microservices architecture and an understanding of the characteristics of each language. I can implement backend, OAuth2 authentication, DB SQL tuning, BFF construction, and develop in conjunction with the front-end. Also, I have controlled WebFlux in Spring5 and implemented real-time events through PubSubAPI. He understands the importance of separating the front-end, the component philosophy of AtomicDesign, and the communication and representation parts of the development process. I was also responsible for advanced technical challenges such as real-time model playback of robot models using Three.js WebGL and SSE (real-time events). I also have the skills to connect the application layer to the infrastructure layer, such as creating Docker images of each application, and converting simple scripts to CronJobs on k8s.

Recently, I have been interested in team building, and we have been doing YWT review to share the same issues with our current team, user story mapping and use case MTG to avoid missing the features of PJ.

External activities

Tech Blog

- GitHub: https://github.com/yoshiki-0428
- Qiita: https://qiita.com/yoshiki-0428
- Blog: https://tech-blog.yoshikiohashi.dev

Personal Development

- Subsc Media Site Planning, Development the 'minna no subsc' (https://review.subsc.cc/)
- <u>Gatsby Theme Development(https://github.com/yoshiki-0428/gatsby-all-pack-)</u> theme-starter)
- Blog Development(https://github.com/yoshiki-0428/engineer-blog)
- Creating portfolios utilizing 3D models(https://github.com/yoshiki-0428/vue_self_introdude)

Side job

• Development of a CtoC web service that allows each person to post a summary of a book.

Interests and Motivations

- Prefer a development style where the team makes small, quick releases, and then works through a cycle of improvement while receiving user feedback.
- I am good at developing products after conducting user interviews and inception decks in a user-first manner.
- I am relatively good at back-end implementation, but equally capable of front-end implementation. I have no experience in building infrastructure, which I recognize as a weakness.

- Can run CI for some testing and build application-level Docker image builds
- Pair Pro and Mob Pro as a solution for communication in remote work, sharing business logic and transferring skills between teams as much as possible.